<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Datadise</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Datadise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of ACO and GA techniques to generate neural network based Bezier-PARSEC parameterized airfoil</title>
      <link>/publication/aco_ga_ann_waqas_saleem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/aco_ga_ann_waqas_saleem/</guid>
      <description>This research uses Neural Networks to determine two dimensional airfoil geometry using Bezier-PARSEC parameterization. Earlier, Ant Colony Optimization (ACO) techniques have been used to solve combinatorial optimization problems like TSP. This work extends ACO method from TSP problem to design parameters for estimating unknown Bezier-PARSEC parameters that define upper and lower curves of the airfoil. The efficiency and the performance of ACO technique was compared to that of GA. The work established that ACO exhibited improved performance than the GA in terms of optimization time and level of precision achieved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks Based Airfoil Generation for a Given Cp Using Bezier-PARSEC Parameterization</title>
      <link>/publication/ann_based_cp_by_ga_bezier_kharal_aymen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ann_based_cp_by_ga_bezier_kharal_aymen/</guid>
      <description>Determining the airfoil geometry from a given C p-distribution is an inverse problem of paramount importance specially in the context of variable geometry aerodynamic platforms. This work describes the implementation of artificial neural nets for the airfoil geometry determination. Instead of using full coordinates of the airfoil, Bezier-PARSEC 3434 parameters have been used to describe an airfoil. Some of these parameters have been determined using a Genetic Algorithm. In the second stage C p-distribution in terms of cl, cd and cm for 10 angles of attack has been input into three different neural nets for learning and then estimating the corresponding BP3434 parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>